

□ 07841910076 | Sophiedarrouxmartin@gmail.com | Sophiedmartin

Research Interests

I am a PhD student on the i4Health CDT at University College London with an interest in healthcare applications of artificial intelligence. My research focus is on explainable methods and interpretable deep learning in medical imaging. I'm also excited by the use of AI for personalised treatment and enjoy discussions about model bias, fairness and ethics.

Education _

University College London London PHD IN AI & MEDICAL IMAGING 2021 - Present MRES IN MEDICAL IMAGING

Imperial College London London MScI IN PHYSICS (2.I, 68%) 2016 - 2020

St Angela's Ursuline School

A Level: 3A*'s (Maths, Further Maths, Physics) & 1A (History) 2014 - 2016 GCSE: 9A*s (INC. MATHS AND ENGLISH LANGUAGE) & 2As + FMSQ 2009 - 2014

Work Experience _____

Illumina Cambridge

Jul 2019 - Oct 2019 BIOINFORMATICIAN

- I used Python to build a pipeline that used machine learning to identify tumour-only variants from genetic data.
- Explored feature visualisation/engineering methods and hyperparameter optimisation to improve performance.
- I used the Sun Grid Engine cluster computing framework to submit jobs for batch processing.

Open Energi London

DATA SCIENTIST Jul 2018 - Sep 2018

- I contributed to a project to improve asset performance for rapid grid frequency response.
- Code was developed in Python, Git was used to collaborate with other developers and SQL was required to interact with the database.
- I was able to highlight opportunities for business development and presented my findings to the company.

Projects

A Network Science Perspective on Signal Propagation in the Brain

Imperial College London

MSci Research Project

Oct 2019 - May 2020

London

· Supervised by Professor Kim Christensen, I developed a cellular graph network to model excitation spread across structures such as smallworld, stochastic model and Barabasi-Albert hub network. This made use of graph theory and criticality analysis.

Sensitivity Studies of the 5 MeV Distortion at SoLid Utilising Machine Learning

Imperial College London

BSc Research Project

Oct 2018 - May 2019

· Supervised by Dr Daniel Saunders, this project evaluated the use machine learning to detect a distortion in the anti-electron neutrino energy spectrum. This signal vs. background problem is highly transferable and was a useful application of statistical data analysis.

Activities & Responsibilities _

The Blackett Lab Family C.I.C

London

DIRECTOR OF MEDIA & MARKETING

Jun 2020 - Present

• I generate social media content, lead website development, and manage communications for the organisation.

Project Partners London

BOARD TRUSTEE Mar 2020 - Present

• I help facilitate the growth this educational charity by attending meetings and consulting on teaching materials.

Participant Jul 2021 - Sep 2021

• I participated in a 6-week virtual program for selected CS students across EMEA. The program involved technical challenge, YouTube live trainings and interview workshops.

Awards & Publications.

AWARDS

2016 **Winner**, Worshipful Company of Coachmakers and Coach Harness Makers' Jaguar Land Rover Bursary

London

PUBLICATIONS

2021 **Conference Paper,** Development and evaluation of intraoperative ultrasound segmentation with negative image frames and multiple observer labels

ASMUS, MICCAI

Skills_

Programming Python, MatLab, Bash, SQL, Git, LaTeX, Cluster Computing

Web HTML5, CSS, Bootstrap 4, Javascript

General UK Driving License, English (Native), French (B1)